Guide to the Isaiah M. Minkoff Papers and Photographs WAG.086
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Isaiah Minkoff Papers and Photographs
1914-1984
1960-1984
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Minkoff, Isaiah M.
Minkoff, Dussia Samson
Minkoff, Paul
WAG.086
12.25 Linear Feet in 12 record cartons, 9 folders
Isaiah Minkoff served as Executive Secretary of the Jewish Labor Committee, Executive Director of the General Jewish Council, and the Executive Director of the National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC -- later NCRAC).. In addition to his responsibilities in organizational work, Minkoff continued contact with people around the world, many of whom he had assisted in the Holocaust and postwar years, and Russian-speaking socialists who had been the inspiration of his youth. While they are very incomplete, and mostly date from Minkoff's last three decades of public life, the papers include material that spans the whole range of his interests and accomplishments.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Isaiah Minkoff (1901-1983) was born in Warsaw in 1901 and was raised and educated in Moscow. As a teenager he became involved in World War I relief work and also became active in a number of Jewish and socialist organizations. After the Revolution of 1917 he continued his political activity as a member of the Russian Social Democratic movement and served a one-year term in Soviet prisons. He attended the University of Moscow, 1918-1920. He fled the Soviet Union, and in 1922 arrived in California, where he completed his B.A., in Slavonic languages, at the University of California, Berkeley, in 1926.
In June 1926 he married Dussia Samson, daughter of Russian Jews who had emigrated to the United States after a long residence in Harbin, China, and settled in San Francisco. The Minkoffs soon resettled in New York, where he soon became active in Jewish communal affairs. In New York be became reacquainted with a large circle of Russian Social-Democratic (Menshevik) exiles who had fled from the Soviet Union after the consolidation of Bolshevik power.
From 1936 to 1941 he served as Executive Secretary of the Jewish Labor Committee, and in that capacity played a central role in the JLC'santi-Nazi and rescue activities. For example, Minkoff was one of the chief organizers of the labor-sponsored Counter Olympics held on Randall's Island in New York City in the summer of 1936 (and repeated in the summer of 1937). He also served as the JLC's representative to the Joint Boycott Council, in which the JLC cooperated with Rabbi Stephen Wise's American Jewish Congress to coordinate the consumer boycott of German goods and services. In 1940-41 he was a key figure in the successful effort by the JLC to secure temporary visitors' visas for a list of European labor and socialist activists who were in immediate danger of arrest by the Nazi authorities in France and Eastern Europe. He met with officials of the American Federation of Labor and of the Roosevelt Administration, assisted in the compilation of the visa lists, arranged for transportation of refugees, and on many occasions welcomed the rescued families as they stepped off the boats in New York, Los Angeles or Seattle.
In 1941 he left the Jewish Labor Committee to become Executive Director of the General Jewish Council, a confederation of Jewish defense organizations whose aim was to hammer out joint policies, wherever possible on issues of critical importance during the warsyears, and to make plans for post-war rehabilitation and reconstruction. In 1944 he became the Executive Director of the newly founded Jewish community relations agency, the National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council(NJCRAC -- later NCRAC). He was to hold this position from 1944 until his retirement in 1975, building NCRAC from an umbrella groups of four national agencies and fourteen local communal bodies into a major agency comprised of eleven national and 111 local groups.
NCRAC under Minkoff's leadership became a prime force for Jewish involvement in the civil rights movement, and also fostered a concerted Jewish community response on other issues, such as the reform of U.S. immigrations law, the publicizing of and protest against the plight of Jews in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, support for the state of Israel, and efforts to combat anti-semitism and other forms of bigotry and discrimination in this country and abroad. In addition to his primary responsibilities in NCRAC Minkoff served as a Board member of the Jewish Labor Committee, the Atran Foundation, the Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture, the Conference on Jewish Material Claims against Germany, and the Jewish Daily Forward Association. He was also an active supporter of the YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, the Congress for Jewish Culture and the Workmen's Circle.
In addition to his extensive responsibilities in organizational work, Minkoff kept in touch with a wide circle of friends and comrades around the world -- many of whom he had assisted in the Holocaust and postwar years. He took a deep interest in the fate of Yiddish culture and never lost touch with the Russian-speaking socialists who had been the inspiration of his youth. In his later years he traveled widely in Europe and Israel, and served as a delegate to several international meetings concerned with Jewish communal affairs and the issue of reparations to Holocaust survivors.
Minkoff died of cancer in New York City on May 10, 1983.
Scope and Content Note
While they are very incomplete, and mostly date from Minkoff's last three decades of public life, the papers include material that spans the whole range of his interests and accomplishments. The correspondence series includes a mix of material, incoming and outgoing letters -- both professional and personal, in English, Yiddish and Russian. Included are letters from rabbis and lay Jewish communal leaders, U.S. and Israeli government officials, labor leaders, European socialist politicians, Bundists such as Benjamin Tabachinsky, Left Zionists such as Paul Goldman, and veteran Mensheviks (for example, Boris Sapir, Leo Lande, Gregory Aronson -- and their families). In the subject files are additional groupings of material on individuals with whom Minkoff was especially close; the file on Menshevik leader Raphael Abramovitch, for example, includes correspondence, clippings, Minkoff's memorial tribute, and financial documents relating to Abramovitch's family. The Speeches series includes both notes and full texts, many of them relating to Minkoff's professional duties, but others recounting episodes from his personal and family history, or paying final tribute to departed colleagues, political allies and friends. The photographs series contains images of meetings and conventions that Minkoff attended.
Of particular note is a file of condolence letters written in 1958 on the occasion of the death of Minkoff's brother, the Yiddish writer Nochum Minkoff; letters written on the occasion of Isaiah Minkoff's retirement in 1975 and his serious illness in 1977; correspondence with Kurt Grossman, Fritz Heine, Rudolf Katz and other socialists active in the German resistance to Nazism; long series of grant proposals addressed to the Atran Foundation and the Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture; financial and other data relating to the Special Labor Aid Project (later the Labor Aid Project) -- a JLC initiative to help support aged and needy veterans of the anti-Nazi and socialist movements of Europe; and files of material on the JLC's rescue and aid activities during and immediately after World War II; and many publications and reports of NCRAC and the Jewish Labor Committee.
Arrangement
The papers are comprised of four series: I. Correspondence, II. Subject Files, and III. Speeches, and IV. Photographs
Related Materials
Jewish Labor Committee Records, WAG.025
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Isaiah Minkoff's widow, Dussia Samson Minkoff, in 1992 and 1993. An additional donation was made by Isaiah Minkoff's son, Paul Minkoff, in 1998. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1992.007 and 1992.014.
Clippings (information artifacts); Labor leaders -- United States.; Labor leaders |z Europe.; Socialists |z Europe.; Jews -- Soviet Union; Jews -- United States.; Photographs.; Jews |x Education.; Pamphlets.; Correspondence.; Atran Foundation; Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture; Forward Association; Yivo Institute for Jewish Research; American Federation of Labor; National Community Relations Advisory Council (U.S.); Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); General Jewish Council (U.S.); Minkoff, Dussia Samson; Minkoff, Paul
- Series I: Correspondence, 1940-1984
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1952, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1964-May 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1964-Dec 1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1914-1984
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Abeles, Herbert, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Abramovitch, Raphael, undated, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Human Rights and Genocide, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Address Books, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Aid to Camp Survivors, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Alexandrovitch, Vera, undated, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - American Committee for the Liberation of the Peoples of Russia, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1950-1967 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - American Federation of Jews from Central Europe, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - American Gathering of Jewish Holocaust Survivors, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - American Jewish Commission on the Holocaust, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - American Jewish Commission on the Holocaust, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - American Jewish Committee, undated, 1941-1969 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - American Jewish Conference, undated, 1943, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - American Jewish Congress, undated, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1972, 1975, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Jewish Historical Society: NCRAC Archives, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - American Jewry: General, undated, 1963-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American Labor Conference on International Affairs, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - American Labor Party, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - American Socialist Society, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - American Zionist Council, 1950, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Anti-Communism, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1942, 1948, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Anti-Semitism: Europe, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Anti-Semitism: U.S., 1950, 1960, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute, 1966-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - A. Philip Randolph Memorial Fund, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Apartment: Plan, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Appointment Books, 1979, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Arab Propaganda Activities, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Argentina, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Arendt, Hannah, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Art in Jewish Life, undated, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Association of Jewish Community Relations Workers, undated, 1950-1961 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Association of Jewish Community Relations Workers, 1962-1963, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Atlanta, GA, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Atran Center: Plan, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Atran Foundation, undated, 1948-1961 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Atran Foundation, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Atran Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Atran Foundation, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Atran Foundation (I), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Atran Foundation (II), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Atran Foundation (I), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Atran Foundation (II), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Atran Foundation (I), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Atran Foundation (II), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Atran Foundation (III), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Atran Foundation (I), 1978 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Atran Foundation (II), 1978 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Atran Foundation (III), 1978 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Atran Foundation, Jan 1979-Jun 1979 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Atran Foundation, Jul 1979-Sep 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Atran Foundation, Oct 1979 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Atran Foundation, Nov 1979-Dec 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Atran Foundation (I), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Atran Foundation (II), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Atran Foundation (III), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Atran Foundation, Jan 1981-Mar 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Atran Foundation, Apr 1981-Sep 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Atran Founfdation, Oct 1981-Dec 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Atran Foundation (I), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Atran Foundation (II), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Atran Foundation (III), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Atran Foundation (IV), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Atran Foundation, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Atran Foundation: Budget and Financial Reports, 1970-1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Atran Foundation: "Made in the USA" Film Project, 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Atran Foundation: UJA, 1967-1970, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Atran Frank, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Atran House, undated, 1954, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Atran House, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Atran House, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Austria, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Azeff, Evgeni, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Balkans, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Banewur, Eva, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Baron, W. Salo, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Black Americans to Support Israel Committee, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Blacks and Jews, 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - B'nai B'rith, undated, 1947-1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Brandeis University, 1953, 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Brown, Irving, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Brumberg, Abraham, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Bundist Tribune (Yiddish), 1979 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Carter, Pres., Jimmy, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Central Conference of American Rabbis, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Chanin, Nochum, undated, 1947, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Chernov, Victor, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Civil Rights, 1962-1966 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Clippings and articles: misc., 1953-1981 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Cohen, Jules, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Columbus United Jewish Fund and Council, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Communist Party (U.S.), 1956 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Conference of Presidents of Major Jewish Organizations, 1960-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Conference of Presidents of Major Jewish Organizations, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Conference on the Welfare State, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Conference on Jewish Material Claims Against Germany, undated, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Conference on Jewish Material Claims Against Germany, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Conference on Jewish Material Claims Against Germany, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Congress for Jewish Culture, undated, 1949-1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Coudert, Frederic and Engel M. Irving, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Coughlin, Father Charles, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Council for the Underground Labor Movements of Europe, undated, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Council of Jewish Federations and Welfare Funds, 1947-1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Council of Jewish federations and Welfare Funds, 1963-1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cuba, 1944, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Dector, Moshe, undated, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Detroit, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Development of Jewish Communal Organization in America (Ms. & Notes), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Diary/Appointment Book, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Diary/Appointment Book, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Diary/Appointment Book, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Diary/Appointment Book (Dussia Minkoff), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - DiMarco Reception Committee, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Dreyfus Opera, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Dubinsky, David, 1946, 1952, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Dubnov, Simon, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Eastern Europe, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - East European Jewry, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Educational Alliance, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Einstein, Albert (Atran Proposal), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Eisendrath, Maurice, 1964, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Federation (NYC), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Financial: Contributions, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Forster, Arnold, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - France, 1977, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Franck, Isaac, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Freeland League, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Free World Association, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Gebiner, Benjamin, 1956, 1968, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - General Jewish Council (Archives), undated, 1941-1944 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - General Jewish Council: Hiring of Minkoff, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Germany, 1945-1978 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Ginzberg, Ralph, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Goldberg, B. Z., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Goldenberg, J, undated, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Goldenberg, Yasha, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Goldman, Paul, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Goldstein, A.A., undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Gompers, Samuel, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Grossman, Kurt, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Green, Nancy. L., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Green, William (Bust), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Greenberg, Hayim, undated, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Hagen, Paul: "Deutschland nach Hitler", undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Hashomer Hatzair, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Held, Adolph, undated, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Hertzberg, Arthur, 1964-1980 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Hill, Herbert, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Hillman Foundation, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Hobart College, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Holocaust: General, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Holocaust: General, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Holly Point Project, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Hook, Sidney, undated, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Housepian, Aramais, undated, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Howe, Irving, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Humphrey, Hubert, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hungary, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Illness (Isaiah Minkoff), 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Illness (I. M.) (I), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Illness (I. M.) (II), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Illness (I. M.) (III), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Illness (I. M.) (IV), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Illness (I. M.) (V), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Illness (I. M.), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Interview (I. M.) with John Slawson, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Israel, undated, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Israel, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Israel, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Israel Task Force: Tour, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Jacobson, Philip, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Jewish Community Federation of Cleveland, 1941, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Jewish Community Relations Council of New York, 1950, 1976, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Jewish Culture/History, 1949-1981 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Jewish Daily Forward, 1948, 1959-1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Jewish Daily Forward Association, 1957, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Jewish Daily Forward Association: Finances, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Jewish Encyclopedic Handbooks, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Jewish Image in Televison, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Jewish Labor Bund, 1940-1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1936-1943 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1947-1958 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1971-1975 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: European Trips, 1966, 1974, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: Financial, 1954-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: Minkoff Tribute, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: Projects in Israel, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: Rescue/Immigration, undated, 1940-1943 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: Rescue/Immigration, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: Rescue/Immigration, 1945-1947 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: Rescue/Immigration, 1948-1953 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Newsletter, 1952-1955 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Socialist Farband, undated, 1930-1969 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Jewish War Veterans, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - John Birch Society, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Joint Boycott Council, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Kahn, Tom, ca.1969 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Kallen, Horace, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Kane, Irving, 1949-1953 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Katz, Rudolf, 1952-1961 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Katz, Shlomo, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1963 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Knox, Israel, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Koirala, B. P., 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Labor Aid Project, undated, 1943-1954 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Labor Aid Project, 1959-1961 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Labor Aid Project, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Labor Aid Project, 1964-1967 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Labor Aid Project, 1968-1975 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Labor Aid Project: Ledgers, 1958-1963 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Labor Aid Project: Ledgers, 1963-1969 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Labor League for Human Rights, undated, 1943, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Laidler, Harry, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Lande, Leo, undated, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Landis, Joseph, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, 1963-1980 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - League for Human Rights, Freedom & Democracy, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)